Florencia Petrikovich Software Engineer

London, United Kingdom

fpetrikovich@gmail.com • + 54 (911) 2265-4285 • github.com/fpetrikovich • linkedin.com/in/florencia-petrikovich

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I am a highly motivated software engineer (BS, MEng) experienced in full-stack development, focused on back-end. I'm an energetic learner driven by curiosity and a passion for growth. I have a track record of finding practical solutions to engineering problems while quickly learning and adapting to complex sets of mature systems. Often praised for my high productivity without sacrificing my level of attention to detail. I have experience in big tech companies (Meta) and early-stage, YCombinator-backed startups.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TIENDA CRYPTO Back-end Developer

Buenos Aires, Argentina November 2021 - January 2022

Tienda Crypto is a cryptocurrency exchange startup backed by YCombinator (S2020).

- Streamlined and designed multi-currency bundles for simple purchase of cryptocurrency.
- Constructed a usage analytics system to measure product performance.
- Optimized onboarding process by fixing bugs and optimizing the flow.

META

London, United Kingdom (Remote) August 2021 - October 2021

Software Engineer Intern

- Integrated new infrastructure for data collection, used by internal teams to feed machine learning models.
- Engineered and tested a Hack framework to handle the intersection of user-defined polygons for data labeling.
- Initiated and managed a successful cross-team collaboration with the ML team, the primary customers.
- Improved the ML team's workflow by engineering a configurable system (Hack, GraphQL, React) for their data collection process, reducing the setup time by over 90%.

TIENDA DOLAR Back-end Developer

Buenos Aires, Argentina (Remote) February 2021 - July 2021

Tienda Dolar is a digital currency exchange startup backed by YCombinator (S2020).

- Designed and implemented a TS/Express/MongoDB-powered REST API for a new product.
- Expanded existing codebase with features such as referral & benefits system and a NFT marketplace.
- Facilitated daily front-end team meetings to understand requirements.
- Refactored JS code into layered TypeScript architecture.
- Developed prototype of B2B crypto transaction services.
- Programmed alert system to detect 7+ compliance-related anomalies.

META

Software Engineer Intern

London, United Kingdom January 2020 - March 2020

- Developed automated testing framework for web and mobile visual components using Hack.
- Wrote comprehensive documentation to guide internal teams in successful adoption of the new framework.
- Integrated screenshot results into analytics platforms to visualize components across multiple platforms (Comet, Native, MBasic, etc.) using React.
- Contributed corrections & improvements to existing codebases to ensure accuracy and quality.

EDUCATION

INSTITUTO TECNOLÓGICO DE BUENOS AIRES

Master's Degree in Software Engineering with Honors

Buenos Aires, Argentina January 2021 - December 2022

Focused on Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Data Science, Bioinformatics, Robotics, Cloud Computing, Networking, Security, and Virtual Reality (using Unity).

Capstone Project: Automatic and Customizable Generation of Smart Contracts ERC-721 (NFTs).

INSTITUTO TECNOLÓGICO DE BUENOS AIRES Bachelor's Degree in Software Engineering with Honors

Buenos Aires, Argentina August 2016 - December 2020

SKILLS

Programming Languages/Technologies

Proficient in Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, C, C#, and SQL. Advanced in Hack, GraphQL, CSS/SCSS, HTML, XML, and Solidity. Intermediate in Golang, Ruby, Octave, Matlab, and R.

Databases

Proficient in PostgreSQL, MongoDB, and Redis. Intermediate in CouchDB, Neo4J, AWS DynamoDB, and ElasticSearch.

Frameworks/Libraries

Proficient in React, Node.js, Express.js, Serverless, and Unity. Advanced in Spring (inc. Hibernate), Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-learn, and Biopython.

Software/Tools

Proficient in Unity (VR, Desktop, Mobile), Git, Linux (POSIX). Advanced in Arduino, MEGA11, and BLAST. Intermediate in Blender, Docker, Mercurial SCM, GitHub Actions, and Bitbucket Pipelines.

Languages

Bilingual proficiency in English. Native Spanish. Elementary Japanese.

Certifications

International Baccalaureate Diploma for HL English Language and Literature, SL History, SL Chemistry.

AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Received highest Meta SWE FTE offer (February 2023), but offers were rescinded later.
- Presented a TEDx Talk about the power and benefit of speaking up and breaking the silence which is so daunting to most.
- Third place at Bellatrix's hackathon in 2019.

VOLUNTEERISM

IEEE COMPUTER SOCIETY ITBA

Logistics Member

Buenos Aires, Argentina November 2019 - July 2021

Delivered a comprehensive Git training program to over 1000 university students and professionals. Supported aspiring interns in their job search by providing guidance during workshops.

"UN TECHO PARA MI PAÍS" AND "OPERATION SMILE" Volunteer

Dominican Republic 2012